Guide to the Walter Brattain family papers 1860-1990
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Walter Brattain family papers
1860-1990
1901-1990
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Brattain, Walter H. (Walter Houser)
WCMss.022
35 linear feet 45 boxes
This collection contains the scientific and personal papers of Walter Brattain, an inventor of the transistor and winner of the Nobel Prize in Physics, in addition to his family papers.
Restrictions are noted.
Donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by William and Evelyn Brattain in 1990. The accession number is retro-0023.
Walter Houser Brattain was born on Feb. 10th, 1902 in Amoy, China. He was the son of Ross R. Brattain and Ottilie Houser, the oldest of their five children. Two of his sisters died very young; he spent his childhood in Washington State with his third sister, Mari Brattain, and his brother, R. Robert Brattain. The Brattain family had many Whitman College connections: Ross and Ottilie met at Whitman and Ross graduated from the college in 1901. Walter graduated from Whitman in 1924 with majors in Physics and Math under Professors Benjamin H. Brown (Physics) and Walter A. Bratton (Math).
There were three other physicists of note who graduated in Walter Brattain's class: Walker Bleakney, E.J. Workman, and Vladimir B. Rojansky, with whom he collaborated over the years. The four of them were known as Whitman's "Four Horsemen of Physics." While a Whitman student, Brattain was passionate about math, an excellent tennis player and member of the Kirkman Club, a fraternal group.
After receiving his Bachelor of Science degree from Whitman, Brattain was awarded a Masters of Arts by the University of Oregon in 1926 and a Doctorate of Philosophy by the University of Minnesota in 1929. After completing his graduate studies, Brattain worked for the radio section of the National Bureau of Standards in Washington, D.C., from 1927 to 1928. In 1929 he joined the technical staff of Bell Telephone Laboratories and worked as a research physicist until his retirement in 1976. During World War II, he was associated for 22 months with the National Defense Research Committee at Columbia University, working on magnetic detection of submarines. Brattain was a visiting lecturer at Harvard University during the fall of 1952 and a visiting lecturer at Whitman College between 1962 and 1963, becoming a visiting professor between 1963 and 1972 and an adjunct professor from 1972 until 1976. He remained afterwards as a consultant at Whitman.
Brattain was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1956, with Dr. John Bardeen and Dr. William B. Shockley, "for research on semiconductors and the discovery of the transistor effect." These three American physicists invented the transistor on December 23, 1947, at the American Telephone and Telegraph Company at Bell Laboratories. The transistor's name derives from the descriptive phrase "transfer of signal through varsitor." The transistor is a solid state device involved in connecting battery power to signal power. As a key element in amplifying small electrical signals and in processing of digital information, it is today an active component in all electronic systems. Brattain received honorary Doctor of Science degrees from Portland University in 1952, from Whitman College and Union College in 1955, and from the University of Minnesota in 1957. In 1952 he was awarded the Stuart Ballantine Medal of the Franklin Institute, and in 1954 the John Scott Medal. The degree at Union College and the two medals were received jointly with Dr. John Bardeen, in recognition of their work on the transistor. In 1974, he was named to the National Inventors Hall of Fame.
Brattain was a member of the National Academy of Sciences and the Franklin Institute, a Fellow of the American Physical Society, and a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and the American Association for the Advancement of Science. He was also a member of the commission on semiconductors of the International Union of Pure and Applied Physics and of the Naval Research Advisory Committee. At Whitman, he was nominated to membership in Phi Beta Kappa and Sigma Xi. He also served as an Overseer for the college.
The chief field of Brattain's research was the surface properties of solids, as well as research directed at (1) thermionic emission and absorbed layers on tungsten, phospholipids bylayers or membranes rectification and (2) photo effects at semiconductor surfaces (ergo, cuprous oxide, silicon and germanium). Among his contributions are the discoveries of photo effect at the free surface of a semiconductor, the invention of the point-contact transistor jointly with Dr. John Bardeen, and shared research on piezoelectric frequency standards, magnetometers, blood clotting, and infrared detectors.
Walter Brattain married Dr. Keren Gilmore (chemist) in 1935 and had a son, William G. Brattain, in April, 1943. Keren died in April 1957. In May, 1958, he married Mrs. Emma Jane (Kirsch) Miller, a Whitman College alumna. He had three stepchildren and 10 grandchildren. Walter Brattain died on October 13, 1987, in Seattle, Washington, of Alzheimer's disease.
The collection is divided into two sections: materials created by Walter Brattain in the context of his profession and career (series 1-6), and materials created by the Brattain family (series 7-11).
The Walter Brattain papers contain correspondence between Brattain and his collaborators, Bell Laboratories, Nobel Prize-related correspondence, and letters to other Whitman College alumni. Brattain's writings include his autobiography, speeches, and scientific publications. In addition, the collection contains materials related to his teaching career, research notes, numerous awards and honors, and travels to conferences around the world. The collection also contains photographs of college and reunions, dinner ceremonies and awards, scientific experiments, transistors, and conference trips, specifically those to China and Europe. Rounding out the collection are published scientific papers, awards and diplomas, newspaper clippings, and audio and video recordings.
The Brattain family papers include family histories, correspondence, writings, and photographs. The correspondence series contains letters written or received by members of the Brattain family, including Walter, Ross and Ottilie, Emma Jane, and Keren Brattain. Also included are family and vacation photos. An extensive collection of glass lantern slides documents scenes of daily life in China in the early 1900s. The two groups of materials are not unrelated and some materials might be valuable to both sections but integrated only in one.
Brattain, Walter H. (Walter Houser); Brattain, Keren; Brattain, Emma Jane Miller; Brattain, Ross R.; Brattain, Ottilie; Brattain,, R. Robert; Brattain, William; Brattain, Agnes; Rojansky, Vladimir; Bleakney, Walker
Bell Telephone Laboratories; Bell Telephone Laboratories
Colleges and Universities; Science; Technology
- Correspondence, 1921-1982; 1; 4 linear feet
  Boxes 1-3: General correspondence (incoming and outgoing) arranged by year
  Box 4: Correspondence (incoming and outgoing) arranged by writer or recipien
  - General Correspondence, 1923-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, January-May 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, June-December 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, January-April 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, May-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, January-June 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, January-April 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, May-December 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, January-May 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, June-December 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, January-May 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, June-December 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Autographs, 1979-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Autograph Requests (Denied), 1980-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Roland Bainton Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Walker Bleakney Letter, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - R. Robert Brattain Correspondence and Papers, 1965, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Benjamin Brown Correspondence, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Henry Jackson Correspondence 1, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Henry Jackson Correspondence 2, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - John Scott Award Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lindau Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Mike" Long Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Publishers Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reference Letters, 1963-1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Vladimir Rojansky, 1944-1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Round Robin Letters – Walter Brattain, Vladimir Rojansky, E.J. Workman, and Walker Bleakney, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Donald Rudin and Paul Mueller Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Understanding Science" Lectures Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Whitman College Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Whitman College 50th Anniversary of the Class of 1924 Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nobel Letters and Family Correspondence, 1942-1956 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1966-1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - From Nobel winners to Pope, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Congressmen and President, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Answered Congratulations, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Nobel Prize Congratulations Telegrams, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Nobel Prize Congratulations Letters and Cards, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Nobel Prize Congratulations Letters, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Vladimir Rojansky and Walker Bleakney Letters, 1924-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - From Whitman Alumni to Walter Brattain, 1921-1928 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Harvard Engineering School – Walker Bleakney, 1924-1937 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Letters to and from Vladimir Rojansky, 1924, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Round Robin Booster Letters, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Letters from Walker Bleakney to Walter Brattain, 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Background information on the November 7, 1925, letter of Walker Bleakney to Vladimir Rojansky and Walter Brattain, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - John Bardeen, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Hector Chevigny, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Letters from Wheaton Kraft, 1916-1929 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - William Shockley, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Foreign Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Walter Bratton, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Career, 1917-1989; 2; 11 linear feet
  This series documents Walter Brattain's career as a student and teacher of physics, as well as his scientific research, speeches, and writings. In addition, this series contains information on the conferences he attended and the professional memberships and accolades he received.
  - Teaching, 1953-1971; 1
    Walter Brattain taught at Whitman College from the late 1960s through the early 1970s. He taught several physics courses, as well as general science courses designed to help students "understand natural phenomena."
    - Science 51 Final Exams, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Science 51 Grade Book RESTRICTED UNTIL 2040, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Science 51 Lectures, 1967-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Science 51 Lectures, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Science 51 Lectures, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Science 51 Master Lectures, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Science 51 Mid-Semester, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Science 51 Original Lectures, 1-9, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Science 51 Original Lectures, 10-13, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Science 51 Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Science 51 Review, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Science 52 Exams, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Science 52 Grades, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Science 52 Lectures, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Science 52 Lectures, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Science 52 Lectures, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Science 52 Master Lectures, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Science 52 Notes, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Science 52 Original Lectures 1, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Science 52 Original Lectures 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Science 52 Quiz, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Science 52 Review, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Science 52 Supplementary Material, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Science 51 and 52 Tests, Quizes, and Review Stencils, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Science 51 and 52 Tear Sheets, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - 96B Solid State, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Physics 243 Assignments and Tests, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Physics 243 Experiments, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Physics 243 Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Physics 297 Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Class Names, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Continental Classroom, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Corrected Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cost of Revising Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dates of Talks and Papers for Minnesota, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Grades and Miscellaneous RESTRICTED UNTIL 2040, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Lecture Book Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Master Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Master Lectures Extras, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Minnesota, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Physics of Transistors and Semiconductors Course, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Revised Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Sample Lectures 1 and 12, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Teaching Transistor Physics, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Transcripts of Minnesota Lectures, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - University of Washington Summer Institute, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Differential Equations of Mathematical Physics, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Electrical Engineering Laboring Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Old Exam Questions, Minnesota and Earlier, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Optics, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Physics Department Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Physics Folder, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Spring Quarter Dynamics Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - University of Oregon Advanced Elective Course Notebook, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Transistor-Related Materials, 1940-1984; 2
    This sub-series contains articles, photographs, speeches, and other materials related to the development of the transistor. Included are writings and correspondence by Walter Brattain, as well as materials he collected.
    - "Experiments Leading Up to the Discovery of the Transistor," talk given at conference in Bell Telephone Laboratories, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Articles on Transistor's Invention, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Transistor Promotional Photographs, 1940s (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Transistor Press Releases, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Transistor's Discovery, 1940-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Discovery Photos, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Transistor Memorandum, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Transistor Articles, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Transistor Talks, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "The Story of the Transistor", 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor", undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor" Memorandum, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor" Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor" Pamphlets, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence Regarding Publication of "Genesis of the Transistor", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Published "Genesis of the Transistor", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor" Reference Material, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Transistor Articles, 1948-1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Transistor Patents, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Early Transistor Article Clippings, 1948-1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Tenth Anniversary of the Transistor, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Essay on the Tenth Anniversary of the Transistor, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - 20th Anniversary of the Transistor, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - 25th Anniversary of the Transistor, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - 25th Anniversary of the Transistor 2, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 25th Anniversary of the Transistor 3, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - 25th Anniversary Statement, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Transistor Anniversary and Clippings, 1972-1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Transistor Circuits Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - J. Bardeen and W.H. Brattain, "The Transistor, A Semi-Conductor Tale", 1948 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - J. Bardeen and W.H. Brattain, "Physical Principles Involved in Transistor Action", 1948 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - J. Bardeen, W.H. Brattain, W. Shockley, and G.L. Pearson, "The Transistor and Related Experiments", 1948 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Transistor Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - "Transistor Resisters", undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Charles Weiner, "The Social Inventions Behind the Transistor", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - "The Physics of Transistors and Semiconductors" Booklet, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Bell Labs Correspondence and Soundsheet, 1956-1975 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Press Release - Transistors, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Transistor Clippings, 1948-1987 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Nobel Clippings, 1956-1963 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Transistor and Nobel Publications, 1948-1984 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Walter Brattain, "Discovery of the Transistor Effect: One Researcher's Personal Account," in Adventures in Experimental Physics, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Picture and Data for the First Transistor, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1924-1981; 3
    This sub-series includes handwritten and typewritten manuscripts as well as published articles written or co-authored by Walter Brattain. The bound collections of Bell Telephone Systems monographs include a number of articles by Walter Brattain.
    - Autobiography, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Saga of An Expedition to Stockholm, Sweden, December, 1956" (multiple copies), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Contacts Between Metals and Semiconductors", undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Development of Concepts in Semiconductor Research" Promotional Poster, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dun's Review Statement, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Is the Scientist Morally Responsible for the Use of His Discovery?", undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Harvard Engineering School Exam: Vladimir Rojansky, Walker Bleakney, and Walter Brattain, 1924, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Response to Senator Thomas Henning re: Secrecy and Science, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "How to Justify Scientific Research at the Executive Level – In Government – In Defense Department", undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "The Physics of Transistors," Outline of Speech, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Lecture Promotional Clippings, 1952-1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Lipid Papers, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Local College Talks, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Man and The Universe", 1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Northwest Conference on College Physics – outline of talk and experiment notes, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Meteor Sighting, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Semiconductors," talk given to Metropolitan Section of American Physical Society, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Oscillographic Study of Discharge of Condenser Through Inductance and Resistance and Spark Gap," Thesis, University of Oregon, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Talk given at Phi-Beta Kappa and Stories, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "A Pint's A Pound The World Around", undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Papers, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - The Physics of Transistors and Semiconductors, including "The Copper Oxide Rectifier" by Brattain, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Remarks on NIN Group", undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Reminiscences of 40 Years in Physics", undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - American Institute of Physics History, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Special Talks, 1, 1957-1963 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Special Talks, 2, 1959-1976 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor" Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor," notes and publicity, sponsored by Albuquerque, New Mexico Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Inc., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Speech Given at Dedication of Boeing's Research Building and Speech Given to High School Students, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "Some Points about Surface Phenomena", 1970 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Talks, 1956-1968 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Testimony 1, 1961-1965 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Testimony 2, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Testimony 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Transcripts of Interviews Taken on Tape Recorder, 1964, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - "The University in A Troubled Society", undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Northwest Conference on College Physics, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - "Man and the Universe," Whitman College Centennial Lecture, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - "What is Science?" Washington State University Lecture, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - "Genesis of the Transistor," Washington State University Lecture, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - "Optical Constants of Germanium", 1948 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Continental Classroom, "Physics for the Atomic Age," NBC Television Script, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - W.H. Brattain and W. Shockley, "Density of Surface States on Silicon Deduced from Contact Potential Measurements", 1947 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - W.H. Brattain and L.G. Pearson, "Changes in Conductivity of Germanium Induced by Alpha-Particle Bombardment", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - "Efficiency of Excitation by Electron Impact and Anomalous Scattering in Mercury Vapor," Thesis, University of Minnesota, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - P.J. Boddy and W.H. Brattain, "Electrical Properties of the Anodically Etched Germanium Surface", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 47)